Delmwin Baeka

(+233) 503695535

dbaekajnr@gmail.com • https://www.linkedin.com/in/delmwinb/ 20 Continental Close, Roman Ridge, Ghana

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full Stack Software Engineer with experience leading development teams, building profit generating products across the globe for successful companies with key products processing almost \$1 billion in transactions in the fintech and insurance tech space. Professional experience delivering amazing customer-first products for mobile and web applications using frameworks and tools, such as VueJS, Laravel, Golang, Swift, in a team-based environment. Projects Link: https://dbaeka.com/projects_summary.pdf (non-confidential)

SKILLS

- Programming Languages: PHP, Golang, JavaScript, Swift, C/C++, Python,
- Infrastructure/DevOps: Git, Unix, Linux, Docker, Kubernetes (k8s), Amazon Web Services (AWS), Bash, JIRA, Vault, Gitlab (repo, CI/CD), Vercel, RabbitMQ, Helm, MySQL, PostgreSQL, AWS S3, Redis, DynamoDB, MongoDB
- Frameworks: Laravel, VueJS, Django, Flutter, OpenGL, Flask, FastAPI
- Additional: Testing (PyTest, PHPUnit, Selenium, Appium), Machine Learning (Keras, pyTorch)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Backend Engineer (Contract)

May 2023 - Present

- Buckhill Software UK/Croatia
 Spearheaded the integration of custom modules and features, led RabbitMQ development for distributed services, and crafted scripts for complex insurance rating processes, enhancing functionality and accuracy.
 - Directed development and technical design of two key products, delivering ahead of schedule with over 90% test coverage using CI/CD pipelines.
 - Upheld coding standards, provided feedback during code reviews, and led backend engineer candidate assessments, resulting in two successful hires.
 - Deployed Sentry and OpenTelemetry with Grafana and Loki, accelerating the resolution time for backend exceptions.
 - Orchestrated an EAV database pivot for ETL, applied graph algorithms for schema reconciliation, and ensured seamless CI/CD integration, boosting performance and client satisfaction.

Technology Manager/Lead Software Engineer (Software Engineering) Technology Specialist (Software Engineering) Technology Analyst (Integrations)

Jul 2021 - Aug 2022 Mar 2021 - Jun 2021

Feb 2021- Feb 2021

Zeepay • Accra, Ghana

- Spearheaded and led software development projects with MoneyGram, Ria, Remitly and others to improve remittance redemption across Africa, US and the Caribbean, contributing to an increase in profitability by over 50% for 2021.
- Optimized the performance of existing Payment Gateway processor and Mobile Money platform through code refactoring, SQL and infrastructure optimizations leading to uptime of more than 99.5% uptime and solving recurring downtime issues.
- Engineered architecture and code for mobile money platform on USSD and WhatsApp bot that supports more than 1 million active users in Ghana with an uptime of 99.50% and latency less than 300ms.
- Instituted the use of elastic (ELK) and python scripts for improved log management, observability and application performance monitoring which helped quantify key metrics and influenced a 99.5% uptime of services to clients.

EDUCATION

BSc. Electrical and Computer Engineering

Sep 2016 - Aug 2020

Shanghai Jiao Tong University Joint Institute • Shanghai, China University of Michigan Ann Arbor Joint Institute • Ann Arbor, United States

Awards: SJTU Outstanding Graduate, International Student Scholarship Award, Dean's List

CERTIFICATIONS

- Machine Learning (Coursera) Credential ID: <u>YWBCVZF5YQWD</u>
- Neural Networks and Deep Learning (Coursera) Credential ID: 89WVCXMAX7VG

AWARDS AND HONOURS

2021 Ghana Club 100 (Zeepay)

Awarded officially number 1 company in Ghana for the year under leadership of the tech team

2021 Ultimate Team Player of the Year (Zeepay)

Awarded to employee who contributes and executes diligently during assigned team task and always offers a helping hand